Guide to the David B. Tyack Papers SC1312
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
David B. Tyack Papers
1969-2008
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Tyack, David B.
SC1312
12 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift, 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical / Historical
David B. Tyack was the Vida Jacks Professor of Education and Professor of History, Emeritus at the Stanford Graduate School of Education. He earned his undergraduate degree in 1952 and his PhD in 1958, both from Harvard University. He taught at Reed College from 1959 to 1966, the University of Illinois from 1967 to 1969, and from 1969 to 2016 Stanford University. His primary research focus was the history of American education. David B. Tyack died in 2016.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes teaching files, correspondence, speech files, and research files related to the history of American education.
Tyack, David B.; Tyack, David B.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-098
  - ED 105 (1 of 3), 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ED 105 (2 of 3), 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ED 105 (3 of 3), 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ED 288 (1 of 2), 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ED 288 (2 of 2), 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ED 301 #2 (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ED 301 #2 (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History of Education Lectures ED 201 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History of Education Lectures ED 201 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History of Education Lectures ED 201 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Long View diversity binder contents, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Long View - outliers binder contents, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Revising Inescapable Tensions (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Revising Inescapable Tensions (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Long View #2 Governance Choice binder contents, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - DT Black Teachers/ Caste binder contents (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Public School in Hard Times: the depression years, 1982 Dec (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - C. Kaestie - Fed impact on Gen. Ed Curriculum change, 1979 Aug (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mann consensus (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tyack: law article (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - unlabeled (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Tyack articles (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Onward Christian Soldiers Tyack (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cuban DT Gorre award, 1996-2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Original Gorrs L.C., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lewis Clark talk, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Figure in the carpet? (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ideal teacher- Nerber great, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Possible school BD. Journal AASA, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Article on aging (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pacer Moral educ., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - voucher tack hals, Bost, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - DT MS on politics school, data on ref. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - DT - S. Africa/New Zealand, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Japanese seeking common ground (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rockefeller history, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - DT ed. Leadership civic ed, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - sign; Ricsrp, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - DT McDermott class, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Radio TKK MPR, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - DT Choice - AM prospect, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - DT Lecture on local control - Ed writers, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Pluralism between the ware, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Reviews of Rauter (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - DT yace poems (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - DT Kumeman Forums, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - DT Justice voc ed, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - DT Nais tack re voucher family, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - DT formulating common good (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - comm tack - ed. Conservationism, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - DT article (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Kinloch "ideal teacher" (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - DT history of teacher education, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - DT vouchers, family choice (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - DT misc articles, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - forgotten players DT local school, 1999 July (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Harvard forum, 2003 April 7 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - DT vocational education, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - hand of ideology - school government, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Forums Article (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Coeducation essay - not published (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - talks on photos (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - coeducation (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - notes (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - CTE seminar, 2003 May (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - history (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - CCSRE senior fellow, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - teacher/scholar prog., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - History II Spencer comf., 2006 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Kaied, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - The Spencer Foundation Conference on New Directions in History of Education, 2000 Mar 30-31 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Mexico, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Cal school BDS talk, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - CAL school boards talk, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Bowdoin talk, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Zurich, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Bush talk, 1998 Jul (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Talk on Choice - SUSR (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Bookstore talk seeking (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - CSB interview (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Dean's advisor, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Teacher/scholars SU program, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Teacher/scholar, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Gohzaga talk (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - South Africa - Peter Kalloway, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Montreal - OBS (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Spencer Foundation, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Lazrrton comf. DT (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Manchester Harvard, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Educ. 220D History of School Reform Vol II, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ED 220D Class (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ED 220 ED. Reform MBA (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Educ 220 D. History of School Reform Vol I (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - EDUC 95 Q, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - EDUC 95 Q Sophomore Dialogue on Reform (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pubs (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Custom Course Material ED 105/205 American Education and Public Policy, 1993 Fall (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Course Material, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Alex George (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Public Policy Syllabus: Bakely, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Syllabus - GSPP, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - SIW Course syllabi, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Education Reform: Social Diversity and Constitutional Challenges Education 288 Professor Ted Mitchell, 1992 Summer (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Educational Reform: Social Diversity and Constitutional Challenges Volume II Education 288 Professor Ted Mitchell, 1992 Summer (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - ED 246A Course Reader Teachers and Constitution instructor: Tyack, 1995 Summer (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Custom Course Material Stanford In Washington (SIW) Education 233X Public Policy and Education Elisabeth Hansot and David Tyack, 1994 Spring (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Custom Course Material ED 105 American Education and Public Policies Instructor: Kirst/Tyack, 1992 Fall (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - ED 105 American Education and Public Policy Professors Kirst and Tyack, 1998 Fall (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Research Report The Sarah Roberts Case of 1849 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - inescapable Tensions: Common schools in a diverse society (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - ED 201 vol 11 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 201, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - ED 301 Historiography, 1993 Sep (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Step Cobstitution (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Maine Zurich, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ED 105 Vol 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 301 Historiography (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Packet on civic quiz - Naturalization, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Sophomore Dialogue Syllabi, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Immigration (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Citizenship Course, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - DT Teach Euglue Do Citizenship, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Managers of the millenium: A history of leadership in american public education (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - On French Revolution, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dupre Krieger (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Urban Underclass Materials (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Old notebooks, circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Old public polls on education, 1940-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Gallup Polls on Education, 1969-1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Gallup Polls, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Voices from the Past, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Citizenship tests (1 of 2), 1986-2008 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Citizenship tests (2 of 2), 2006 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - INS 100 Questions Other citizenship, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - APSA Institutions and their Environments: The Historical Case of the Schools, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Elt/DT Depression (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Common Goods Elt. Notes for Berkeley Seminar, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - AERA (1 of 2), 1992 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - AERA (2 of 2), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Gores Award, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Tyack Institute Play (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - ORT Talk, Spring 1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Resume: Tyack, 1983-1995 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Hist.Ed. Conference, 1971-2000 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Tyack MSS, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1995-2002 (Box 8, Folder 19)